Dorchester, Boston, Mass. Second Church records, 1770-1991.
Congregational Library Archives
- Institutional records, 1805 1987; 1805-1987; 232 Items
  - Meetings, 1806 1967; 1806-1810, 1848-1967; 18 Items
    - Announcement of Next Meeting, undated (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - Incorporation and by-laws, 1807 1986; 1807-1986; 15 Items
    This sub-series contains by-laws, covenants, declaration of faiths and act of incorporation for Second Church.
    - By-Laws, June 19, 1807 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Covenants, 1808 1852; 1808, 1852 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - Amendment to the Act of Incorporation, 1818 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - The Covenant and Declaration of Faith of the Second Church of Christ in Dorchester with a List of Officers and Members, 1828 (Box 33, Volume 1)
    - Agreement of Association (duplicate), March 17, 1887 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - By-Laws, 1913 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - By-Laws, 1913 1972; 1913, 1923, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Organization of Second Church, 1922 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Copies of Constitution and By-Laws, 1924 1986; 1924, 1972, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - Incorporation and By-Laws, 1926 1932; 1926-1932, undated (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Revisions of By-laws, 1932 1940; 1932-1940 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Preamble to the Constitiution, undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Proposed new "Confession of Faith and Covenant", undated (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Covenant and Confession of Faith, undated (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Article III, Section 23 of By-Laws, undated (Box 25, Folder 27)
  - Church records, 1807 1987; 1807-1987; 58 Items
    This sub-series contains various church records, meeting records, reports, memos, ballots, and benevolence records.
    - Church records, 1807 1853; 1807-1853 (Box 4, Volume 1)
    - Church meetings, 1808 1958; 1808-1958 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - Church records, 1809 1848; 1809-1848 (Box 16, Volume 1)
    - John Codman and Second Church Society, June 2, 1813 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Church records, 1848-12-30 1904-12-23; December 30, 1848 - December 23, 1904 (Box 4, Volume 3)
    - Church records, 1849-03 1913-03; April 1849 - April 1913 (Box 4, Volume 2)
    - Ecclesiastical Council credentials, 1893 1907; 1893-1907 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Records and reports A-C, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Records and reports D-K, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Records and reports L-P, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Records and reports P-T, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Records and reports T, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Records and reports T-Z, 1896-01-01 1903-12-31; January 1, 1896 - December 31, 1903 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Reports and memos S-T, 1900 1905; 1900-1905 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Church records (1 of 5), 1900 1921; 1900-1921 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Church records (2 of 5), 1900 1921; 1900-1921 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Church records (3 of 5), 1900 1921; 1900-1921 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Church records (4 of 5), 1900 1921; 1900-1921 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Church records (5 of 5), 1900 1921; 1900-1921 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Reports and memos A-H, 1904-01-01 1908-01-01; January 1, 1904 - January 1, 1908 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Reports and memos H-N, 1904-01-01 1908-01-01; January 1, 1904 - January 1, 1908 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Reports and memos N-S, 1904-01-01 1908-01-01; January 1, 1904 - January 1, 1908 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Reports and memos U-Z, 1904-01-01 1908-01-01; January 1, 1904 - January 1, 1908 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Church records, 1905-01-27 1922-02-03; January 27, 1905 - February 3, 1922 (Box 9, Volume 1)
    - Church reports and memos A-K, 1908-01 1913-12; January 1908 - December 1913 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Church reports and memos L-P, 1908-01 1913-12; January 1908 - December 1913 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Church reports and memos P-S, 1908-01 1913-12; January 1908 - December 1913 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Church reports and memos T-Z, 1908-01 1913-12; January 1908 - December 1913 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Church reports and memos S-T, 1908-01 1913-12; January 1908 - December 1913 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Church records, 1908 1922; 1908-1922 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Society and parish records, 1908 1923; 1908-1923 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Manual, January 23, 1914 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Church records book A-C, 1914 1922; 1914-1922 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Church records book D-G, 1914 1922; 1914-1922 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Church records book H-M, 1914 1922; 1914-1922 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Church records book N-T, 1914 1922; 1914-1922 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Church records book T-Z, 1914 1922; 1914-1922 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Church records A-C, 1915 1920; 1915-1920 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Church records C-G, 1915 1920; 1915-1920 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Church records G-M, 1915 1920; 1915-1920 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Church records M-S, 1915 1920; 1915-1920 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Church records S-Z, 1915 1920; 1915-1920 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Church records, 1920 1925; 1920-1925 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Church council secretary reports, 1922 1924; 1922-1924 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Second church ballots, 1922 1930; 1922-1930 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Standing committee records, 1923-02 1931-01; February 1923 - January 1931 (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Request for officers, February 25, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Second Church ballots, 1931 1957; 1931-1957 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Church records, 1967-1977 (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - Official ballots, 1968 1969; 1968-1969 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Benevolence records, 1969 1974; 1969-1974 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Benevolence records, 1975 1979; 1975-1979 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Office and Committee members, 1977 1986; 1977-1986 (Box 28, Folder 39)
    - Thanksgiving plate list, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Benevolence records, 1980 1983; 1980-1983 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Church records, 1980 1983; 1980-1983 (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Church records, 1981 1982; 1981-1982 (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - Consideration of Leaving UCC, January 5, 1987 (Box 28, Folder 40)
  - Publications, 1848 1995; 1848-1995; 47 Items
    This sub-series contains published materials such as morning worship, newspaper articles, bulletins, postcards, surveys and histories.
    - Morning Worship, 1848 1980; 1848, 1968-1980 (Box 25, Folder 55)
    - Norton's Improved Calendar, 1858 (Box 31, Folder 42)
    - Congregational Quarterly on John Codman, January 1860 (Box 31, Folder 43)
    - Excerpts from "The Advantages and Disadvantages of an Ecclesiastical Society in Connection with a Church", July 1877 (Box 31, Folder 44)
    - Around the Lamp: A Paper for Young People, February 1892 (Box 31, Folder 45)
    - Church Calendar, 1892-02 1892-03; February - March 1892 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Dedication of Kimball Union Academy, September 6, 1892 (Box 31, Folder 46)
    - Westminster Lesson Leafs, July 1894 (Box 31, Folder 47)
    - Calendar, December 30, 1894 - January 5, 1895 (Box 31, Folder 48)
    - History of Second Church by Reverend Arthur Little (copy 1), January 27, 1898 (Box 25, Folder 53)
    - History of Second Church by Reverend Arthur Little (copy 2), January 27, 1898 (Box 25, Folder 54)
    - Postcards, 1898-1917 (Box 31, Folder 49)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1908 1985; 1908-1985 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1914 1970; 1914-1970 (Box 31, Folder 81)
    - Bulletins, 1916 1932; 1916, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Campaign Poster for Charles A. Ufford, 1920 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Advance Reports of Massachusetts Congregational Conference, 1923-1931 (Box 31, Folder 50)
    - Sowing Seed for A More Abundant Harvest, March 22, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Morning Worship, 1936-01-05 1936-04-05; January 5 - April 5, 1936 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Morning Worship, 1936-04-12 1936-09-20; April 12 - September 20, 1936 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Morning Worship, 1936-09-27 1936-12-27; September 27 - December 27, 1936 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Lent and Holy Week Services, 1941 1942; 1941-1942 (Box 31, Folder 51)
    - Bulletins, 1945 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Bulletins, 1946 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Plans and Procedures for the Local Church, 1946 1947; 1946-1947 (Box 31, Folder 52)
    - Bulletins, 1947 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Bulletins, 1948 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Newsletters, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 53)
    - Newsletters, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 54)
    - Newsletters, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 55)
    - Newsletters, 1971 1972; 1971-1972 (Box 31, Folder 56)
    - In Literary through the Bible, December 1972 (Box 31, Folder 57)
    - Morning Worship, 1977 1981-09-16; 1977 - August 16, 1981 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Newsletters, 1979 1980; 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 57)
    - Monthly Newsletters, 1979 1986; 1979-1983, 1986 (Box 25, Folder 58)
    - Morning Worship, February 10 - April 6, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Lynn Woods Reservation History and Map, 1981 (Box 31, Folder 58)
    - Morning Worship, 1981-09-23 1982-11-28; August 23, 1981 - November 28, 1982 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Morning Worship, 1982-12-05 1986; December 5, 1982 - 1986 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Newspaper Articles on Church Arson, 1983 (Box 31, Folder 82)
    - Congregational Survey, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 73)
    - Articles about Second Church Controversies, 1985 1987; 1985-1987 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - World Mission Magazine, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 70)
    - Meditations of a Layman, undated (Box 31, Folder 59)
    - Church Welcoming Notice, undated (Box 31, Folder 60)
    - "Faith of Our Fathers": Historical Pageant of Second Church, undated (Box 31, Folder 61)
    - Civil War Period Facts of History Connected with Dorchester Second Church by Henry Clap Kendall, undated (Box 11, Volume 2)
  - Photos and phonographs, 1882 1955; 1882-1883, 1955; 5 Items
    This sub-series contains photos of Thomas W. Bickneel, Mayor John B. Hynes, Second Church watercolor and a lithograph of St. Peter's church.
    - Portrait of Thomas W. Bickneel, 1882 (Box 31, Folder 65)
    - Watercolor of Second Church, 1883 (Box 31, Folder 66)
    - Portrait of Mayor John B. Hynes, July 21, 1955 (Box 31, Folder 67)
    - Photographs of Reverends, undated (Box 31, Folder 68)
    - Lithograph of St. Peter's Church, undated (Box 11, Item 1)
    - Doodle-oodle Dee (Fields Morris), undated (Box 33, Reel 1, File 1)
      Copy of Song
      A version of the song can be found here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZvRxhZeNhVc
    - Tennessee, I Hear You Calling Me (Robe-Godfrey), undated (Box 33, Reel 1, File 2)
      A digital version of the song can be viewed here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jumj7Hg-CC8
    - It's Nice to Get Up in the Mornin' (Harry Lauder), undated (Box 33, Reel 2, File 1)
      A digital version of the song can be viewed here: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Qm148aG_g4
    - When the Bonnie, Bonnie Heather is Blooming (I'll Return Annie Laurie to You) (James G. Ellis), undated (Box 33, Reel 2, File 2)
      A digital version of the song can be viewed here (this video uses an edison cylinder instead of an edison disc): https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TQjhbgtxIpQ
  - Board of deacon's records, 1905-03-19 1984-09-22; March 19, 1905 - September 22, 1984; 5 Items
    This sub-series contains Board of Deacon's records for the Second Church.
    - Board of Deacon's records, 1905-03-19 1922-01-08; March 19, 1905 - January 8, 1922 (Box 2, Volume 1)
    - Board of Deacon's records, 1922-03-12 1931-11-08; March 12, 1922 - November 8, 1931 (Box 2, Volume 2)
    - Board of Deacon's records, 1932-03-13 1950-03-07; March 13, 1932 - March 7, 1950 (Box 2, Volume 3)
    - Board of Deacon's records, 1950-05-09 1966-09-13; May 9, 1950 - September 13, 1966 (Box 2, Volume 4)
    - Board of Deacon's records, 1966-01-10 1984-09-22; October 1, 1966 - September 22, 1984 (Box 2, Volume 5)
  - Church committee records, 1918 1972; 1918-1972; 4 Items
    This sub-series contains church committee records.
    - Church Committee records, 1918 1926; 1918-1926 (Box 17, Volume 5)
    - Church Committee records, 1926 1931; 1926-1931 (Box 17, Volume 6)
    - Church Committee records, 1932 (Box 17, Volume 8)
    - Church Committee records, 1953 1972; 1953-1972 (Box 17, Volume 9)
  - Board of trustees reports, 1921 1983; 1921-1983; 10 Items
    This sub-series contains Board of Trustees reports and annual corporate meetings.
    - Trustees and Annual Corporate Meetings, 1921 1924; 1921-1924 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Board of Trustees records, 1922-02-01 1924-05-12; February 1st, 1922 - May 12th, 1924 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - Board of Trustees record book, 1924-05-24 1930-01-08; May 24, 1924 - January 8, 1930 (Box 33, Volume 5)
    - Trustees and Annual Corporate Meetings, 1925 1936; 1925-1936 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Board of Trustees records, 1929 1935; 1929-1935 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Trustees and Annual Corporate Meetings, 1937 1947; 1937-1947 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Trustees and Annual Corporate Meetings, 1948 1957; 1948-1957 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Board of Trustees Reports, 1962 1965; 1962-1965 (Box 31, Folder 41)
    - Board of Trustees' Correspondences, 1967 1983; 1967, 1982-1983 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Board of Trustees Minutes, 1965 1967; 1965-1967 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Annual reports, 1922 1987; 1922, 1935, 1968-1987; 15 Items
    This sub-series contains annual reports from Second Church.
    - Annual Report, 1922 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Annual Meeting Reports, January 24, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - Committee Annual Reports, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 59)
    - Committee Annual Reports, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 60)
    - Committee Annual Reports, 1970 (Box 25, Folder 61)
    - Committee Annual Reports, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 62)
    - Committee Annual Reports, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 63)
    - Committee Annual Reports, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 64)
    - Committee Annual Reports, 1974 (Box 25, Folder 65)
    - Annual Reports, 1976 1979; 1976-1979 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - Annual Reports, 1977 1980; 1977-1980 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Annual Reports, 1980 1985; 1980-1985 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Annual Reports, 1981 1983; 1981-1983 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Annual Reports, 1984 1986; 1984-1986 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Annual Reports, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Secretary reports, 1978 1987; 1978-1987; 4 Items
    This sub-series contains secretary reports from the Second Church.
    - Secretary Reports, 1978 1980; 1978-1980 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Secretary Reports, 1981 1983; 1981-1983 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Secretary Reports, 1984 1985; 1984-1985 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Secretary Reports, 1985 1987; 1985-1987 (Box 27, Folder 22)
- Finances, 1806 1989; 1806-1989; 129 Items
  This series contains financial information such as accounts, records, receipts, banking, donations, weekly offerings, trust funds, quarterly returns, income, budgets and treasurer records.
  - Accounts, 1806 1988; 1806-1988; 15 Items
    This sub-series contains information on disbursement and fund accounts.
    - Second Church Accounts, 1806 1889; 1806-1889 (Box 15, Volume 1)
    - Second Parish Accounts, 1806 1866; 1806-1866 (Box 15, Volume 2)
    - Fund Accounts, 1924 1927; 1924-1927 (Box 15, Volume 4)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1931-10 1936-12; October 1931 - December 1936 (Box 6, Volume 3)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1937-01 1942-02; January 1937 - February 1942 (Box 6, Volume 4)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1942-03 1946-12; March 1942 - December 1946 (Box 6, Volume 5)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1947-01 1952-03; January 1947 - March 1952 (Box 7, Volume 2)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1952-04 1957-12; April 1952 - December 1957 (Box 13, Volume 1)
    - Disbursement Accounts and Income, 1958 1963; 1958-1963 (Box 13, Volume 2)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1958-01 1963-07; January 1958 - July 1963 (Box 7, Volume 3)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1963-09 1968-12; September 1963 - December 1968 (Box 7, Volume 4)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1969-01 1973-12; January 1969 - December 1973 (Box 7, Volume 5)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1874 1978; 1974-1978 (Box 8, Volume 2)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1979 1984; 1979-1984 (Box 8, Volume 3)
    - Disbursement Accounts, 1985 1988; 1985-1988 (Box 8, Volume 4)
  - Records, 1807 1988; 1807-1837, 1867-1988; 45 Items
    This sub-series contains financial records such as ledgers, tax book, salaries, annuity fund and reports.
    - Second Parish Assessors book, 1807 1837; 1807-1837 (Box 17, Volume 1)
    - Mortgage and Financial Records, 1867 1897; 1867-1897 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - Order to Transport for Mary Houghton, October 2, 1868 (Box 28, Folder 60)
    - Tax Book, 1880 1916; 1880-1916 (Box 15, Volume 5)
    - Pulpit Supply records, 1887 (Box 19, Volume 1)
    - Vouchers, 1900 (Box 29, Folder 63)
    - Financial Ledger (1 of 2), 1915 1925; 1915-1925 (Box 28, Folder 61)
    - Financial Ledger (2 of 2), 1915 1925; 1915-1925 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Financial Packet, 1915 1925; 1915-1925 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Financial Correspondences, 1916 1922; 1916-1922 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - Benevolent Organization Financial Ledger, 1917 1919; 1917-1919 (Box 18, Volume 12)
    - National War Band Committee, 1918 (Box 29, Folder 65)
    - Benevolent Societies Financial Ledger, 1925 1926; 1925-1926 (Box 19, Volume 4)
    - Benevolent Financial Ledger, 1920 1921; 1920-1921 (Box 19, Volume 6)
    - Financial Records, 1920 1925; 1920-1925 (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - Financial Ledger, 1922 1925; 1922-1925 (Box 15, Volume 7)
    - Assessors Report, 1923 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Church Monetary Fund Records, 1923 1960; 1923-1960 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Building Fund of Phillips Congregational Church, November 20, 1924 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Financial Records, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Financial Ledger, 1927 1928; 1927-1928 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Financial Ledger, 1936 (Box 15, Volume 6)
    - Finances and Pledge Cards, 1936 1937; 1936-1937 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Church Finances, 1937 1965; 1937-1965 (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - Church Finance, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Financial Transactions, 1955 1959; 1955-1959 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - Salaries, 1963 1965; 1963-1965 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Special Committee on Minister's Salaries, July 6, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Salaries, 1966 1969; 1966-1969 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Annuity Fund Letter, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 68)
    - Payroll, 1970 1977; 1970-1977 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - Supporting Schedules and Finances, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Financial Reports, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 47)
    - Financial Reports, 1979 1987; 1979-1987 (Box 29, Folder 48)
    - Finance Committee Correspondences, 1980-04 1981-10; April 1980 - October 1981 (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Financial Information, 1980 1981; 1980-1981 (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - Financial Records, 1980 1983; 1980-1983 (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - Financial Information, 1980 1983; 1980-1983 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Forms for Anne L. Meekin, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 69)
    - Financial Records, 1981 1982; 1981-1982 (Box 29, Folder 51)
    - Financial Reports, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 58)
    - Financial Reports, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 59)
    - Financial Reports, 1987-1988 (Box 29, Folder 60)
    - Financial Records (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 29, Folder 61)
    - Financial Records (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 29, Folder 62)
  - Receipts, 1820 1972; 1820-1878, 1972; 6 Items
    This sub-series contains common stock and receipts of Second Church.
    - Receipts, 1820 1829; 1820-1829 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Receipts, 1840 1847; 1840-1847 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Receipts, 1807 1819; 1807-1819 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Receipts, 1832 1837; 1832-1837 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Receipts, 1848 1878; 1848-1878 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Common Stock and Receipts, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer, 1867 1986; 1867-1986; 17 Items
    This sub-series contains treasurer's accounts, record books, reports and treasurer's payments.
    - Second Parish Treasurer, 1867 1912; 1867-1912 (Box 15, Volume 3)
    - Treasurer's record book, 1890 1921; 1890-1921 (Box 17, Volume 2)
    - Payments and Treasurer's Reports A-S, 1891 1915; 1891-1915 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Payments and Treasurer's Reports T-Z, 1891 1915; 1891-1915 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Treasurer's records, 1905 1921; 1905-1921 (Box 19, Volume 2)
    - Treasurer's record book, 1912 1915; 1912-1915 (Box 24, Volume 1)
    - Treasurer's record book, 1913 1921; 1913-1921 (Box 17, Volume 4)
    - Treasurer's Annual reports, 1914 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Treasurer's Account records, 1926 1934; 1926-1934 (Box 17, Volume 7)
    - Treasurer's Account book, 1935-01 1938-10; January 1935 - October 1938 (Box 33, Volume 6)
    - Treasurer's Account book, 1928-11 1942-09; November 1938 - August 1942 (Box 33, Volume 7)
    - Treasurer's Account book, 1942-09 1946-09; September 1942 - August 1946 (Box 33, Volume 8)
    - Treasurer's Account book, 1947-01 1952-04; January 1947 - April 1952 (Box 33, Volume 9)
    - Treasurer's Account book, 1952-05 1959; May 1952 - 1959 (Box 33, Volume 10)
    - Treasurer's Report, 1963 1968; 1963-1968 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Treasurer's Report, 1969 1977; 1969-1977 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Treasurer's Report, 1978 1986; 1978-1986 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Banking, 1904 1987; 1904-1925, 1960-1987; 14 Items
    This sub-series contains bank records, financial statements, investments, check stubs, securities and expenditures.
    - Suffolk Branch Expenditures, 1904 (Box 29, Folder 64)
    - Investments, 1922 (Box 29, Folder 66)
    - Securities of Second Church, April 1, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 67)
    - Check Stubs, 1960 1961; 1960-1961 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Check Stubs, 1961 1962; 1961-1962 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Check Stubs, 1970 1972; 1970-1972 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - Check Stubs, 1972 1973; 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - Bank Records, 1980 1981; 1980-1981 (Box 29, Folder 49)
    - Bank Statements, 1984 1985; 1984-1985 (Box 29, Folder 52)
    - Financial Statements (1 of 2), 1985 1988; 1985-1988 (Box 29, Folder 53)
    - Financial Statements (2 of 2), 1985 1988; 1985-1988 (Box 29, Folder 54)
    - Bank Statements, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 55)
    - Bank Statements and Deposit Slips (1 of 2), 1987 (Box 29, Folder 56)
    - Bank Statements and Deposit Slips (2 of 2), 1987 (Box 29, Folder 57)
  - Donations, 1925 1982; 1925, 1960-1982; 4 Items
    This sub-series contains donations and bequests to the Second Church.
    - Donation Receipt for Henry B. Morse from Parish House, November 28, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Donations, 1960 1964; 1960-1964 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Donations, 1963, undated (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Donations and Bequests, 1980 1982; 1980-1982 (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Weekly offerings, 1928 1989; 1928, 1982-1989; 9 Items
    This sub-series contains the weekly offering reports.
    - Weekly Offerings Financial Ledger, 1928 (Box 19, Volume 5)
    - Weekly Offerings, [1982] (Box 6, Volume 1)
    - Weekly Offerings, 1983 (Box 7, Volume 1)
    - Weekly Offerings, 1984 (Box 8, Volume 1)
    - Weekly Offerings, 1985 (Box 13, Volume 3)
    - Weekly Offerings, 1986 (Box 13, Volume 4)
    - Weekly Offerings, 1987 (Box 13, Volume 5)
    - Weekly Offerings, 1988 (Box 13, Volume 6)
    - Weekly Offerings, 1989 (Box 13, Volume 7)
  - Trust fund, 1946 1981; 1946-1981; 8 Items
    This sub-series contains trust fund records and reports.
    - Trust Funds, December 31, 1946 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - Trust Funds Detail, 1954 1975; 1954-1975 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Reports and Trust Funds, 1961 1963; 1961-1963 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Trust Fund Deposit records, 1961 1981; 1961-1981 (Box 18, Volume 13)
    - Trust Fund Annual Reports, 1964 1972; 1964-1972 (Box 24, Folder 1)